Guide to the Independent Order of Odd Fellows Records of California Lodges
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Independent Order of Odd Fellows Records of California Lodges
1852-1967
WA MSS S-2961
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6.09
(7 boxes)
Independent Order of Odd Fellows
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: July 1972 Acquisition; January 2004 Acquisition; and July 2006 Acquisition.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The Independent Order of Odd Fellows is a fraternal organization. The Order was founded in Britain, and the American branch of the organization was founded in Baltimore, Maryland in 1819. The Order opened to women in 1851 with the founding of the Rebekah branch.
Scope and Contents
Financial records and receipts, account books, membership records, meeting minutes, reports, correspondence, circulars, and ephemera generated by the activities of the Charity Lodge No. 6 of Stockton and the Hanford Lodge, the Lady of the Lake Rebekah Lodge No. 111, and the Lucerne Lodge (all located in Hanford), as well as other California-based Independent Order of Odd Fellows lodges and encampments.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from William P. Wreden on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1972; purchased from Vigilante Rare Documents on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2004; and purchased from Carmen D. Valentino on the Ramona Lazare Fund, 2006.
Women -- Societies and clubs; Fraternal organizations -- California; Women -- West (U.S.); California -- Social life and customs -- 19th century; California -- Social life and customs -- 20th Century; Account books -- California -- 19th century; Account books -- California -- 20th Century; Minutes (administrative records) -- California -- 19th century; Minutes (administrative records) -- California -- 20th Century; Receipts (financial records) -- California -- 19th century; Receipts (financial records) -- California -- 20th Century; Independent Order of Odd Fellows; Independent Order of Odd Fellows. Charity Lodge No. 6 (Stockton, Calif.); Independent Order of Odd Fellows. Lady of the Lake Rebekah Lodge No. 111 (Hanford, Calif.); Independent Order of Odd Fellows. Hanford Lodge (Hanford, Calif.); Independent Order of Odd Fellows. Lucerne Lodge (Hanford, Calif.)
- July 1972 Acquisition, 1852-1919; Series I; 0.42; (1 box)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from William P. Wreden on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1972.
  Arrangement
  This portion of the collection is arranged alphabetically by file type.
  - Financial and membership records of various lodges, 1854-1919 (Box 1)
  - Financial and membership records of various lodges, 1868-1919 (Box 1)
  - Membership records of various lodges, 1853-1908; 3 (Box 1)
  - Reports and meeting minutes, primarily for Charity Lodge No. 6 (Stockton, Calif.), 1853-1919 (Box 1)
  - Unsorted records, 1852-1893; 2 (Box 1)
- January 2004 Acquisition, 1874-1967; Series II; 4; (4 boxes)
  Purchased from Vigilante Rare Documents on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2004.
  This portion of the collection is organized into four series: Hanford Lodge, Lady of the Lake Rebekah Lodge 111, Lucerne Lodge 275, and Unsorted Lodges.
  - Hanford Lodge (Hanford, Calif.)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains material pertaining to the Hanford Lodge of Hanford, California. Other material concerning the Hanford Lodge may be present in the "Unsorted Lodges" series.
    - Reports and letters, 1911-1929 (Box 2)
    - Blank checks, undated (Box 2)
    - Roll of officers, lodges 189 and 164, 1887-1897 (Box 2)
    - Meeting minutes, Lodge 264, 1887-1890 (Box 2)
    - Meeting minutes, Encampment 68, 1900-1904 (Box 2)
    - Meeting minutes, Encampment 68, 1931-1938 (Box 2)
    - Meeting minutes, Encampment 68, 1939-1946 (Box 2)
    - Meeting minutes, Encampment 68, 1947-1967 (Box 2)
    - Recorder's monthly reports, Lodge 189, 1889-1890 (Box 2)
    - Recorder's monthly reports, Lodge 164, 1899-1901 (Box 2)
    - Enrollment registry, unidentified lodge or encampment, 1902-1913 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's receipt book, Lodge 264, 1887-1892 (Box 2)
    - Account book, Encampment 68, circa 1916-1952 (Box 2)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee appointed by Encampment 68, 1907-1908 (Box 2)
    - Receipt books for Executive Committee, 1908-1908; 4 (Box 2)
    - Annual reports, 1925-1927 (Box 2)
    - Semi-annual reports, 1891-1895 (Box 2)
    - Semi-annual reports, 1911-1927; 2 (Box 2)
    - Annual relief reports, 1891-1924 (Box 3)
    - Report of the permanent secretary, 1891-1893 (Box 3)
    - Membership applications for Lodge 264, 1879-1898; 5 (Box 3)
    - Receipts, 1891-1899 (Box 3)
    - Postcards, 1889-1909 (Box 3)
  - Lady of the Lake Rebekah Lodge 111 (Hanford, Calif.)
    Contains material pertaining to the Lady of the Lake Rebekah Lodge 111 of Hanford, California. Other material concerning the Lady of the Lake Rebekah Lodge 111 may be present in the "Unsorted Lodges" series.
    - Checks, 1903-1924; 2 (Box 3)
    - Roll of officers, 1887-1904 (Box 3)
    - Roll of officers, 1905-1928 (Box 3)
    - Meeting minutes, 1887-1892 (Box 3)
    - Meeting minutes, 1892-1897 (Box 3)
    - Account book, 1884-1902 (Box 3)
    - Receipt book, 1888-1892 (Box 3)
    - Receipt book, 1899-1909 (Box 3)
    - Receipt book, 1928-1929 (Box 3)
    - Receipt book, 1929-1929 (Box 3)
    - Receipt book, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Delinquent dues book, 1897-1907 (Box 3)
    - Semi-annual reports, 1911-1915 (Box 3)
    - Bills and receipts, 1886-1949; 2 (Box 3)
    - Certificates, 1911-1960 (Box 3)
    - Checks, 1892-1923 (Box 3)
    - Dues, 1908-1908 (Box 3)
  - Lucerne Lodge 275 (Hanford, Calif.)
    Contains material pertaining to the Lucerne Lodge 275 of Hanford, California. Other material concerning the Lucerne Lodge 275 may be present in the "Unsorted Lodges" series.
    - Meeting minutes, 1907-1909 (Box 3)
    - Meeting minutes, 1912-1914 (Box 3)
    - Roll of officers, 1902-1914 (Box 3)
    - Blank book of notice of arrearage forms, undated (Box 3)
    - Semi-annual report, 1904-1904 (Box 3)
  - Unsorted Lodges
    - Applications, 1889-1913; 3 (Box 4)
    - Bills, checks, and receipts, 1923-1936; 2 (Box 4)
    - Bills, 1894-1957; 9 (Box 4)
    - Certificates, 1874-1924; 4 (Box 4)
    - Checks and receipts, 1890-1923; 10 (Box 4)
    - Grand Lodge of the State of California circulars, 1890-1929; 5 (Box 4)
    - Forms, 1891-1911 (Box 4)
    - Grand Army of the Republic circulars, 1889-1896; 6 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1883-1895 (Box 4)
    - Member lists and financial records, 1903-1929 (Box 4)
    - Unsorted ephemera and correspondence, undated (Box 4)
    - Unsorted printed material, undated (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1893-1914; 4 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1904-1933; 2 (Box 4)
    - Grand Army of the Republic circulars, 1889-1892 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1895-1932; 2 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1888-1939; 11 (Box 5)
    - Envelopes, 1889-1931; 7 (Box 5)
    - Fraternal Aid Association members roll book, 1897-1907 (Box 5)
    - Unsorted reports, circulars, and correspondence, 1895-1934; 7 (Box 5)
    - Ceremonies for opening, conducting the business, and closing subordinate lodges, 1908-1908 (Box 5)
    - Published programs for opening and closing lodges, 1896-1896; 3 (Box 5)
    - Reports, bonds, and leases, 1884-1940; 5 (Box 5)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 5)
    - Patriarchs Militant program and report, 1905-1905 (Box 5)
    - California Odd Fellow and New Age newsletter, 1908, 1916, 1918 (Box 5)
    - Receipts, 1906-1906 (Box 5)
    - Patriarch Militant ceremonial braid, undated (Box 5)
- July 2006 Acquisition, 1870-1913; Series III; 1.67; (2 boxes)
  Purchased from Carmen D. Valentino on the Ramona Lazare Fund, 2006.
  This portion of the collection is arranged chronologically.
  - Colfax Lodge Records, 1870-1913
    - Dues ledger for Colfax Lodge 132, 1870-1880 (Box 6)
    - Meeting minutes ledger for Colfax Lodge 132, 1900-1913 (Box 7)